There are three types of questions, yes-no, either-or, and the five W questions.
They each have a different inflection pattern, so even if you don't catch all
the words, you can still tell what type of question it was. The five W questions are
who, what, where, when, and why, and how. As you heard in the question response
above, where's the book? It's on the table. The inflection goes up on the
question and down on the statement. A query like, would you like tea or coffee?
Could be an either or question. Tea? Coffee? Or a yes no question. Would you
like tea or coffee? Hot beverage? A classic, probably apocryphal story spells
out the consequences of misinterpreting the question type. An immigrant was
passing through Ellis Island and was asked the then standard question, are you
planning to overthrow the United States by force or violence? The man pondered deeply
for a moment and tentatively replied, by force? Of course, he was not let in, as
the only acceptable answer was no.